LEIGH B. BIENEN PAPERS (APAP312) 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Reference Materials, 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated; 5; 8.2
  - Ronald Tabak, "Execution of Injustice: Under Any Test, Death Penalty Fails", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ronald J. Tabak, "Review of Law & Social Change", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - United Nations Social Development - Capital Punishment, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - United States General Accounting Office Report to Senate and House Committee on the Judiciary - Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Amendment to House of Representatives Bill 3371 - Equal Justice Act, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - American Criminal Law Review, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The American University Law Review, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Amnesty International - The Death Penalty List of Abolitionist and Retentionist Countries, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Articles by Craig Haney, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mark Ballard, "Judges Clogging Death - Penalty Docket; Harris DA's Study finds Half of Cases Await Decisions", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Michael Booth, "Kwiatkowski convicted in ex-wife's strangling, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - William J. Bowers and Margaret Vandiver, "New Yorkers want an Alternative to the Death Penalty", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - David I. Bruck, "Does the Death Penalty Matter? Reflections of a Death Row Lawyer", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Leigh Dingerson, "Reclaiming the Gavel: Making Sense Out of the Death Penalty Debate in State Legislatures", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Easy Access - version 1.0, National Center for Juvenile Justice, 1991 (Floppy-disk 3)
  - Gallup Poll, "Death Penalty Support Remains Strong, But Most Feel Unfairly Applied", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Valerie P. Hans and Neil Vidmar, "The American Jury at Twenty-Five Years", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Harmelin v. Michigan, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Rhonda G. Hartman, "Critiquing Pennsylvania's Comparative proportionality Review in Capital Cases", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Robert A. Harvie, "Where Is The Man? The Search for a Juvenile court in Montana", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - House of Representatives Bill HR.2851, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - House of Representatives Bill 2851 - Fairness in Death Sentencing Act, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Wayne King, "Defiant Widow Seeks to Reopen Lindbergh case", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Bruce Ledewitz, "Sources of Injustice in Death Penalty Practice: The Pennsylvania Experience", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mark Mauer, "Americans Behind Bars: A Comparison of International Rates of Incarceration", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Carrie Menkel-Meadow and Shari Seidman Diamond, "The Content, Method, and Epistemology of Gender in Sociolegal Studies", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Lori L. Nader, "Walton v. Arizona: the Confusion Surrounding the Sentencing of Capital Defendants Continues", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Nalini K. Pande, "The Death Penalty and the Mentally Retarded Defendant; Diminished Culpability and Inadequate safeguards", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Glenn L. Pierce, "Florida Law Review, Choosing Those Who Will Die: Race and the Death Penalty in Florida", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Glenn L. Pierce, "Florida Law Review: Choosing Those Who Will Die: Race and the Death Penalty in Florida", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Recap: Capital Litigation, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Statement of John J. Curtin, Jr. and James S. Liebman concerning Fairness and Efficiency in Habeas Corpus Adjudication, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Heather Strong, "Homicides in Australia" (with letter), 1991; 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ronald J. Tabak, "Justice Brennan and the Death Penalty", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Ronald J. Tabak and J. Mark Lane, "Albany Law Review: Judicial Activism and Legislative 'Reform' of Federal Habeas Corpus: A Critical Analysis of Recent Developments and Current Proposals", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - ABA Journal, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Articles on Proportionality Review from Deborah W. Denno, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bureau of Justice Statistics Special Report, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Drucilla Cornell, "Gender, Sen and Equivalent rights", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Shari Seidman Diamond, Jonathan D. Casper, "Blindfolding the Jury to Verdict Consequences: Damages, Experts, and the Civil Jury", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Florida State University Law Review, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lonny J. Hoffman, "The Madness of the Method: The Use of Electrocution and the Death Penalty", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lifelines, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lifelines, No. 56, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Mental Retardation and Physician Aid-in-Dying, 1992; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Otey v. State of Nebraska - Brief and position papers, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "Prosecutor v. Scientist: A Cat-and-Mouse Relationship", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Michael R. Rand "The Study of Homicide Caseflow: Creating a Comprehensive Homicide Dataset", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Michael J. Saks and Peter David Blanck, "Justice Improved: The Unrecognized Benefits of Aggregation and Sampling in the Trial of Mass Torts", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Socio - Legal Bulletin, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - U.S. Department of Justice Statistics - Capital Punishment 1992 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Margo I. Wilson and Martin Daly, "Who Kills Whom in Spouse Killings? On the Exceptional Sex Ratio of Spousal Homicides in the United States", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Alabama Death Penalty cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Arizona Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Ursula Bentele, "Race and Capital Punishment in the United States and South Africa", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Jonathan D. Casper and Kennette Benedict, "The Influence of Outcome Information and Attitudes on Juror Decision making in Search and Seizure Cases, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Philip J. Cook and Donna B. Slawson, "The Costs of Processing Murder Cases in north Carolina", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Court Opinion - Gacy v. Welborn, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Daubert v. Merrell Dow Pharmaceuticals, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - John M. Dauson and Barbara Boland, "Murder in Large urban Counties, 1988", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Death Penalty Information Center Year End Report, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Delaware Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Shari Seidman Diamond, "Instructing on Death: Psychologists, Juries, and Judges", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - David Erickson, "Capital Punishment at what price: And Analysis of the cost issue in a strategy to abolish the death penalty", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Florida Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - John Wayne Gacy v. George Welborn, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Idaho Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Kentucky Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Louisiana Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Maryland Death Penalty cases, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Kendra Meinert, "Criminal Injustice: Continuing Racial Inequities In Death Penalty Sentencing", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Mississippi Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Missouri Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Montana Death Penalty Cases, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Nevada Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - New Mexico Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - John T. Noonan, Jr., "Horses of the Night: Harris v. Vasquez", 1993; 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ohio Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Oklahoma Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joanna Piepgrass, "The Woman, the rapist, and the condom: Violence and (Mis)Representation in the Austin, Texas Rape Case, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Robert Rosenthal and Peter David Blanck, "Science and Ethics in Conducting, Analyzing, and Reporting Social Science Research: Implications for Social Scientists, Judges, and Lawyers", 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - David A. Ruhnke, United States v. Pretlow - Defendant Pretlow's Brief and Appendix in Support of Death Penalty Motions, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - US Military Death Penalty Cases, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - United States v. Antar, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Peter David Blanck, "Communications Technology for Everyone: Implications for the Classroom and Beyond", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Book of the States volume 30, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - William J. Bowers, Margaret Vandiver and Patricia H. Dugan, "A New Look at Public Opinion on Capital Punishment: What Citizens and Legislators Prefer", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Deborah W. Denno, "Testing Penry and it's Progeny", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Shari S. Diamod, "Instructions Frequently Baffle Jurors, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Federal Bills on racial Discrimination and the Death Penalty - House Bill 1102, Senate Bill 440, 1994; 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Jurors: The Power of 12 Report of the Arizona Supreme Court Committee on More Effective Use of Juries, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Jury Project: Report to the Chief Judge of the State of New York, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Jury Project: Report to the Chief Judge of the State of New York, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Jack Kevorkian Juror Questionnaire, ca. 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - James Luginbuhl and Michael Burkhead, "Sources of Bias and Arbitrariness in the Capital Trial", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Legislative Profile Report - Senator Joseph R. Biden, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - C.R. Mann's references, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Policy Conference Policy Task Force Manual - Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, Princeton University, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Racial Disparities in Federal Death Penalty Prosecutors 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Shepard's Military Justice Citations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - State Court Administrators, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - O.J. Simpson Juror Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - O.J. Simpson Juror Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - O.J. Simpson Juror Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Summary of and Preliminary Guidance Concerning The Crime Bill (Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Syllabus - Language and Law, Professor Beth Mertz, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Peter Tiersma, "Dictionaries and Death: Do Capital Jurors Understand Mitigation", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Donald H. Wallace and Jonathon R. Sorensen, "Missouri Proportionality Review: An Assessment of a State Supreme Court's Procedures in Capital Cases", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - David Zuckerman, "Preliminary Report on the Rate of Death Penalty Exposure in Philadelphia County", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "A Symposium on the Death Penalty", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - ABA Journal, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - James R. Acker and Charles S. Lanier, "Matters of Life or Death: The Sentencing Provisions in Capital Punishment Statutes", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Article on reinstatement of Death Penalty in New York, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Bureau of Justice Statistics, Federal Habeas Corpus Review: Challenging State Court Criminal convictions, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Stephen B. Bright and Patrick J. Keenan, "Judges and the Politics of Death: Deciding Between the Bill of Rights and the Next Election in Capital Cases", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The Champion, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Conference - Capital Punishment: Is There Any Habeas Left in This Corpus?, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Lawrence J. Connell, Analysis of First Degree Murder Cases, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - The Death Penalty in the Twenty - First Century, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Patricia H. Dugan, et. al., "Massachusetts Legislators' Crime and Justice Policy Preferences," Report of a study conducted by students of the College of Criminal Justice, Northeastern University, ca. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Douglas Lee Eckberg, "Estimates of Early Twentieth - Century U.S. Homicide Rates: An Econometric Forecasting Approach", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Douglas Lee Eckberg, "Estimates of Early Twentieth - Century U.S. Homicide Rates: An Econometric Forecasting Approach", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Erik Eckholm, "Studies Find Death Penalty Often Tied to Victim's Race", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Effective Death Penalty Act of 1995 (H.R.729) (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Nancy Gertner, "Book Review: Is the Jury Worth Saving?", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Hendirk Hartog, "Coercion and Harriet Douglas Cruger", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Nancy Mathis, "GOP begins major rewrite of crime bill; Democrats wow all-out fight", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Michael Mello, "Adhering to Our Views: Justices Brennan and Marshall and the Relentless Dissent to Death as Punishment", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - New York Court of Appeals - Statement Accompanying Release of Death Penalty Rules for Public Comment, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - New York Legislation reintroducing the Death Penalty, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - New York Reimposition of death penalty, 1995; 1996 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - New York State Assembly Death Penalty Debate, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - New York State Bar Association Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Death Penalty Legislation, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - New York State Capital Punishment Act, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New York State Death Penalty Debate - Senate Bill 2469, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New York State Death Penalty Debate - Senator Stephen M. Saland, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New York State Senate minutes - Bill number 2850 (imposition of the death penalty), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New York state death row and executions locations, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - New York Times Magazine - Los Angeles Police Department, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Robbin S. Olge, et. al., "A Theory of Homicidal Behavior Among Women", 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Pre-Trial motion for challenging the constitutionality of Pennsylvania Death Penalty, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Preparation Time for 21 U.S.C. 848 Federal Death Penalty Trials, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - O.J. Simpson, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ronald J. Tabak "Are Executions in New York Inevitable?", 1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Texas death penalty cost, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - United States v. Antar, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - United States v. Maloney, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Appellate Capital Cases Issues in the U.S. Courts: Local Rule + Operating Procedures, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bracy v. Gramley, Collins v. Welborn (US Court of Appeals, Seventh Circuit, 1995), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Delaware - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Joseph P. Fried, "Brooklyn Case is City's First Seeking Death", 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Judicial Business of the United States Courts of the Seventh Circuit July 1,1995 Thru June 30,1996, ca. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Law and Human Behavior, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Donald Loftin Juror Questionnaire, ca. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Michael L. Radelet, William S. Lofquist, and Hugo Adam Bedau, "Prisoners Released from Death Rows Since 1970 Because of Doubts About their Guilt", 1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - United States v. Timothy James McVeigh and Terry Lynn Nichols, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Robert N. Wilentz Obituary, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Brief and Appendix of Amicus Curiae of the coalition concerned about the Execution of the Innocent on behalf of Ronald Kliner ( Illinois v. Kliner ), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Female Homicide Victims in New York City, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Focus on Law Studies, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Richard Rosenfeld, "Changing Relationships Between Men and Women", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Richard Rosenfeld, "Changing Relationships Between Men and Women, A Note on the Decline in Intimate Partner Homicide", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Eric Baumer et. al., "The Influence of Crack Cocaine on Robbery, Burglary, and Homicide Rates: A Cross - City, Longitudinal Analysis", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Champion, National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, 1998; 2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Conference: Socially - Assisted Dying: Media, money + Meaning, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Samuel R. Gross, "Update: American Public Opinion on the Death Penalty - It's Getting Personal", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - NAACP Legal Defense Fund Contact List, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Christopher Slobogin, "Psychiatric Evidence in Criminal Trials: To Junk or not to Junk?", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Lawrence M. Solan, "Law, Language, and Lenity", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - People v. Collins (Illinois, 1985), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - United States v. Baltazar Saenz, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - James R. Acker and Charles S. Lanier, "Ready for the Defense? Legislative Provisions Governing the Appointment of Counsel in Capital Cases", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Jeffrey S. Adler, "The Negro Would be More Than an Angel to Withstand Such Treatment", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Article titles by R. George Wright and John H. Culver, 1999; 2000 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - John Blume, Theodore Eisnberg, and Martin T. Wells, "Explaining Death Row's Population and Racial Composition", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Laura Dugan et. al., "Explaining the Decline in Intimate Partner Homicide", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Franzen v. Birkett, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - David Kocieniewski, "Trenton Court Upholds Law on Executions", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Law and Human Behavior, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Jeffrey J. Pokorak, "Deadman Talking: Competing Narratives and Effective Representation in Capital Cases", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Jason M. Schoenberg, "Making the Constitutional Cut: Evaluating New York's Death Penalty Statute in Light of the Supreme Court's Capital Punishment Mandates", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Bruce A. Arrigo and Christopher R. Williams, "New England Journal on Criminal and Civil Confinement Summer, 1999", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Articles by Phyllis L. Crocker, 2000; 2001 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Richard R. W. Brooks, "Fear and Fairness in the City: Criminal Enforcement and Perceptions of Fairness in Minority Communities, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Bush V. Gore decision, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Markus Dirk Dubber, "The Historical Analysis of Criminal Codes", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Eric M. Freedman, "Milestones in Habeas Corpus", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - M. Catherine Healy, "New England Journal on Criminal and Civil Confinement Summer, 1994", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Homicide Studies, 2000; 2002 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - James S. Liebman, et. al., "A Broken System: Error Rates in Capital Cases, 1973-1995", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - James S. Liebman, "Columbia Law Review The Overproduction of Death", 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - David C. Baldus, et. al., "The Disposition of Nebraska Capital and Non-capital Homicide (1973-1999): A Legal and Empirical Analysis Final Report, Volume 1", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - David C. Baldus, et. al., "The Disposition of Nebraska Capital and Non-Capital Homicide Cases (1973-1999): A Legal and Empirical Analysis - Volume 2, Tables, Figures, and Appendices", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - David C. Baldus, et. al., "The Disposition of Nebraska Capital and Non-Capital Homicide Cases (1973-1999): A Legal and Empirical Analysis - Volume 3, Technical Appendices", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Susan Bandes Articles, 2001; 2002; 2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bracy and Collins v. Schomig and Cowan, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Case Study on State and County Costs Associated with Capital Adjudication in Arizona: Data Set III Research Report to Arizona Capital Case Commission, 2001; 2010 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Samuel R. Gross, "Second Thoughts: Americans' Views on the Death Penalty at the Turn of the Century", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bill Jenkins, "What to do When the Police Leave: A Guide to the First Days of Traumatic Loss", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Michigan v. Jack Kevorkian - Pretrial Questionnaire, ca. 2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ronald J. Tabak Article and Reply with letter, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - American Bar Association: Ten Principles of a Public Defense Delivery System, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Articles by Nancy S. Marder, 2001; 2002 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Deborah W. Denno, "When Legislatures Delegate Death: The Troubling Paradox Behind State Uses of Electrocution and Lethal Injection and What it Says About Us", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Richard C. Dieter, "Blind Justice: Juries Deciding Life and Death with only Half the Truth", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dignity Denied: The Experience of Murder Victims' Family Members Who Oppose the Death Penalty, published by Murder Victims' Families for reconciliation, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Sean Groom, "Death Penalty Lawyers", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Paul J. Haase, " 'Oh My Darling Clemency': Existing or Possible Limitations on the use of the Presidential Pardon Power", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Illinois v. Ballard, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Illinois v. George H. Ryan, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - William S. Lofquist, "Putting Them There, Keeping Them There, and Killing them: An Analysis of State-Level Variations in Death Penalty Intensity", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Lawrence C. Marshall, "Do Exonerations Prove that 'The System Works?'", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Lisa Madigan, "Time to act on reforms is now", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Material for the Italian Parliament - "La pena di morte nel mondo, nel diritto internazionale e nei Parlamenti dell'Unione Europea" (The Death Penalty in the world, in international law, and in the Parliaments of the European Union), 2002; 2004 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Material for the Italian Parliament - "Abolizione della pena di morte" (Abolition of the Death Penalty), 2002; 2004 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Texas report on failures of state criminal court, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - United States v. Quinones (U.S. District Court), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Criminology, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Criminology + Public Policy, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Deal OK'd on death penalty reforms; Compromise paves way for bill to pass in fall veto session", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "Death Row in Ohio, 2003: The Case for a Study Commission", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Nora v. Demleitner, "Fordham Urban Law Journal", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Nancy J. King, "The Origins of Felony Jury Sentencing in the United States", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Lawrence C. Marshall, "The Innocence Revolution and the Death Penalty", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Performance Audit Report: Costs Incurred for Death Penalty Cases (Kansas), 2003 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Michael L. Radelet, "Capital Punishment in Colorado: 1859-1972", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - State of Connecticut Commission on the Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Scott Turow, "To Kill or Not to Kill", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - United States v. Sampson, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Katherine Baicker, "Advances in Economics Analysis & Policy", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Katherine Baicker, "The Budgetary Repercussions of Capital Convictions", 2003; 2010 (Box 6, Folder 41)